Guide to the Student Academic Records 1888-2009
Oregon State University Libraries, Special Collections & Archives Research Center
Student Academic Records
1888-2009
1888-1961
Oregon State University Libraries, Special Collections & Archives Research Center Special Collections & Archives Research Center 121 The Valley Library Oregon State University Corvallis, OR 97331-4501 Phone: 541-737-2075 Email: scarc@oregonstate.edu Web: http://scarc.library.oregonstate.edu
RG 053 - SG 2
Oregon State University. Registrar.
355 cubic feet 817 boxes, including 3 oversize boxes
496 microfilm reels
The Student Academic Records document students enrolled at Oregon State University from the late 1880s through early 2000s. The records include official transcripts, applications for admission, high school and other college transcripts, and related documents. The Registrar's Office was established in about 1903 with John B. Horner as the first Registrar.
Historical Note:
Prior to 1900, the Clerk of the College kept all student records in ledger books. This early office in the Administration Building (now Benton Hall),was part of the President’s Office. The Registrar’s Office as an official function is first mentioned in the Oregon Agricultural College Catalog of 1903. Professor John B. Horner (1856-1933) held the title of first Registrar. The Registrar’s office originally had responsibility for recruitment of students, admissions, registration, and maintenance of student permanent academic records. In 1960, a separate Admissions Office was established at Oregon State University.
The Student Academic Records document students enrolled at Oregon State University from the late 1880s through early 2000s. The records include official transcripts of courses, grades, and degrees completed; applications for admissions; high school and other college transcripts; and related documents assembled by the Registrar's Office for an individual student's record.
Current student academic records are maintained in electronic form by the Registrar's Office.
Student academic records for students that are deceased are open for research. All other student academic records are restricted.
The Student Academic Records consist of 5 series: I. Student Record Book and List of Matriculates, 1888-1901; II. Bound Student Academic Records, 1900-1915; III. Student Academic Records, circa 1904 - circa 1961; IV. Microfilmed Student Academic Records, 1892-2009; and V. Microfilmed Academic Record Locator Cards, 1976-1979.
These records were transferred to the OSU Archives in numerous accessions from 1998 to 2010.
The Administrative Council Records (RG 032) include a Register of Students and Students Grades for 1869-1871. The Registrar's Office Records (RG 053 - SG 1) include administrative records documenting student enrollment policies and procedures at Oregon State. The Special Collections & Archives Research Center's holdings include the John B. Horner Papers.
Horner, John B., 1856-1933.
Oregon Agricultural College--Students.; Oregon State Agricultural College--Students.; Oregon State College--Students.; Oregon State University--Students.; Oregon State Agricultural College. Registrar.; Oregon State College. Registrar.
College registrars--Oregon--Corvallis.; College students--Oregon--Corvallis.; College student records--Oregon--Corvallis.; Student registration--Oregon--Corvallis.
Colleges and Universities; Oregon; Corvallis
- Student Record Book and List of Matriculates, 1888-1901; Series I
  Series I documents students enrolled at Oregon Agricultural College from 1888 to 1901 in a Student Record Book for 1888-1901 and a List of Matriculates for 1888-1896.
  - Student Record Book, 1888-1901 (Box 1)
    The student recordbook includes entries for students who attended Oregon Agricultural College from 1888 to 1901. The book has this title on the spine, Class Standing and College Record, State Agricultural College of Oregon and consists of 3 sections for the fields of study -- Agricultural, Mechanical, and Household Economy. Entries within these sections are in chronological order by first enrollment. An alphabetical index of students names is at the beginning of the volume.
  - List of Matriculates, 1888-1896 (Box 2)
    The List of Matriculates of The State Agricultural College of Oregon includes students who were enrolled at Oregon Agricultural College from September 1888 through September 1896. For each student, the list provides a student number; full name; age; home "post office", county, and state; the date of entrance; college history (degree program); remarks; and the parent's or guardian's name and address. The list indicates the year of enrollment for the student (first, second, etc.). For a few entries, the list indicates when a student completed their degree. This volume also includes summary information on the number of students by Oregon county.
- Bound Student Academic Records, 1900-1915; Series II
  Series II consists of 10 bound volumes of early student academic records for students enrolled in 1900-1915 as well as unbound documents for the same time period. These are for records numbers 000007 through 005080. Record numbers were assigned to a set of documents that were in alphabetical order, hense the documents are in both alphabetical and numerical order. Some documents with these record numbers are also available on microfilm in Series IV.
  - Volume One; 001239 - 001629 (Abbott - Calkings) (Box 3)
  - Volume Two; 001630 - 002022 (Calloway - Duckworth) (Box 4)
  - Volume Three; 002023 - 002417 (Dudley - Greear) (Box 5)
  - Volume Four; 002418 - 002813 (Greear - Hunsaker) (Box 6)
  - Volume Five; 002814 - 003198 (Hunsaker - Luse) (Box 7)
  - Volume Six; 003199 - 003589 (Lutgens - Naill) (Box 8)
  - Volume Seven; 003590 - 003987 (Naito - Richardson) (Box 9)
  - Volume Eight; 003988 - 004384 (Richardson - Spence) (Box 10)
  - Volume Nine; 004385 - 004776 (Spence - Wanstrom) (Box 11)
  - Volume Ten; 004778 - 005080 (Watrous - Zwicker) (Box 12)
  - Unbound Documents 000007 - 002664 (Box 13)
  - Unbound Documents 002671 - 003818 (Box 14)
  - Unbound Documents 003821 - 005080 (Box 15)
  - Oversize Document 005016 (Wood, John Rollo) (Box 2)
- Student Academic Records, circa 1904 - circa 1961; Series III
  Series III consists of original student academic records for students enrolled from the early 1900s through early 1960s with record numbers 005081 through 106999. The records are arranged in rough chronological order as the numbers were assigned as when students enrolled for their first term at Oregon State. The name index to record numbers is available in Series V. These records include Oregon State transcripts, applications, high school and other college transcripts, military discharge documents, and foreign school documents. The Oregon State transcripts are also available on microfilm in Series IV. Beginning with record 076899, the documents have not been processed and are still housed in the original folders and record storage boxes. Legal-size and oversize documents have been separated and are listed at the end of this series. Note: Separation sheets for oversize materials that are filed with letter-size documents may direct a user to a superceded box number or location; current box numbers for oversize materials are listed at the end of this series.
  Student academic records for students that are deceased are open for research. All other student academic records are restricted.
- Microfilmed Student Academic Records, 1892-2009; Series IV; 427 microfilm reels and 1 cubic foot of paper records
  Except for some earlier records also found in bound volumes, this series only includes microfilm of the official transcript. The microfilm reels in this series, through reel 299, are labeled with "SAR" preceding the reel number on the microfilm box.
- Microfilmed Academic Record Locator Cards, 1976-1979; Series V; 69 microfilm reels
  Series V consists of Academic Record Locator Cards that serve as an name index for the student academic records. The cards are arranged alphabetically by last name and provide the student's name and the associated record number for their student academic record. The bulk of the series (reels 8-70) consists of cards maintained by the Registrar's Office as of 1976 that were microfilmed at that time. Alphabetical additions to the card file were filmed in 1977 (reels 71-72); 1978 (reels 73-74); and 1979 (reels 75-76).